A Guide to the National Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors, 1970-2000
Library of Virginia
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - ADERP History and Reports (Box 16)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports--13-15 (1978) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports--16-18 (1978-1979) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports--19-21 (1979-1980) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports 1981 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ADERP--Quarterly Reports 1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Virginia (Box 17-22)
  - Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Virginia 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 2-8)
  - Virginia 1976-1979 (Box 18, Folder 1-9)
  - Virginia--1976-1979 (Study Review Seminar) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Virginia 1980-1984 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Virginia 1985-1989 (Box 19, Folder 7-10)
  - Virginia 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 1-7)
  - Virginia 1990-1995 (Box 20, Folder 8-11)
  - Virginia State Substance Abuse Plan--FY 1979 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Virginia State Substance Abuse Plan--FY 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Comprehensive State Plan--1985-1990 Vol. I: A Responsible Transition (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Comprehensive State Plan--1985-1990 Vol. II: System Overview, Issues, and Profiles (Box 21, Folder 5-10)
  - Virginia Alcohol Services Plan FY 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 5-10)
  - Comprehensive Community Alcohol Plan 1975 (Box 22, Folder 5-10)
  - Progress Report--State Alcoholism Plan--1 July 1972 - 31 December 1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Interagency Comprehensive Substance Abuse Plan 1989 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Virginia--Background of alcohol counselors 1975 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Virginia--Registry; addresses and phone numbers (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Virginia--Alcoholism: A Directory of Services (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Virginia--Alcoholism Programs in Commonwealth of Virginia (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Virginia--Report of the Department of Welfare and Institutions 1973 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Directory of Treatment Resources (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Virginia--Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Employee Programs and Insurance (Box 23-25)
  - Employment (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Employee Assistance Certification Commission (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Employee Assistance Professionals Association, Inc. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Employee Assistance Programs (Box 23, Folder 5-9)
  - Employee Assistance Programs--Articles (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Employee Assistance Programs--Models (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - EAP--Publications (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - EAP Workshop--26-27 January 1981 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Evaluating Employee Assistance Programs: A Sourcebook for the Administrator and Counselor--November 1981 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Setting up an Employee Counseling Program (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Standards for Employee Alcoholism/Assistance Program (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Crawford Rehabilitation Services--National EAP Service Standards (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - National Council on Alcoholism--Labor Management (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Management Guide on Alcoholism and Other Behavioral Problems (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Anheuser-Busch, Inc.--EAP (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Continental Financial Services, Inc.--EAP (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Reynolds Aluminum--EAP (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Richmond Employee Assistance Program (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - United States Brewers Association, Inc.--EAP (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - United Telecommunications, Inc.--EAP (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Insurance/Health (Box 25, Folder 1-10)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Treatment--Programs, Hospitals, Care Centers (Box 26-30)
  - A Woman's Place (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - ALCENAS (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholic Rehabilitation Center of Central Virginia (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Alcoholic Service Center (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Alcoholism Recovery Center of Virginia (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Beacon (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Brawner Psychiatric Institute (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Carrington Farms (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - C.A.S.P.A.R., Inc. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Center for Perinatal Addiction (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Central Virginia Health Systems Agency (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Central Virginia Substance Abuse Advisory Council (Box 26, Folder 12-14)
  - Central Virginia Substance Abuse Advisory Council--Education & Prevention (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Charlotte Treatment Center (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Charter Colonial Institute (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Charter Medical Corporation (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Charter Westbrook Hospital (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Chit Chat Foundation (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Choices in Recovery (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Circuit Court Alternative Program (Box 26, Folder 22-23)
  - Conifer Park (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - CRC/AODA (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - David C. Wilson Hospital (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Edgehill Newport (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Family Crisis Center (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Father Martin's Ashley (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Fellowship Hall (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Friends of St. John's (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Glenbeigh Hospitals (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Growth & Recovery Opportunities, Inc. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - The Harbours (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Hazelden (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Henrico Informed Parents (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Heritage Health Corporation--Humana Hospital--Humana Hospital, Sebastian FL; Human Hospital St. Luke's, Richmond, VA (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Hidden Brook (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - John Tyler Alcohol Safety Action Program (ASAP) (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Kelly Foundation (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Koala Center (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Lutheran General Hospital (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Mary Washington Treatment Center (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - MCV Referral Directory (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Mediplex (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - MUCH Program (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - National Coalition for Adequate Alcohol Programs (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - National Council on Alcoholism, Inc. (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - National Treatment Consortium, Inc. (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - New Beginnings (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - New Life Center (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - New Life for Youth (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Norfolk Psychiatric Center (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Northern Virginia Psychiatric Group (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Peachford Hospital (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Peninsula Hospital (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Perspectives (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Poplar Springs Hospital (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Pride Institute (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Project Jump Street (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - The Psychiatric Institute (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Psychiatric Institute of Richmond (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Raleigh Hills Hospital (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Richmond Aftercare (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Alcohol Safety Action Program (ASAP) (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Metropolitan Hospital (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Resources (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Richmond Treatment--John Lancaster (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Ridgeview Institute (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Riverside Hospital (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Rubicon (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Safe Centers (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Sage Crossing (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - St. John's Hospital (Box 28, Folder 16-18)
  - St. John Vianney Center (Box 28, Folder 19-21)
  - St. Mary's Hospital (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Schick Shadel Hospitals (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Self Health Systems (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Serenity House (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Sharp Cabrillo Hospital (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Shealy Institute (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Shenandoah Counseling Associates (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Skills Matrix Project (Box 29, Folder 8-11)
  - Smith Alcoholism Center Rehabilitation Unit (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Southern Health Services (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Stuart Circle (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Sun Coast Hospital (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Tidewater Psychiatric Institute (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Tucker Pavilion Chippenham Medical Center (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Turtle Island Center for Alternatives (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Valley Forge Medical Center & Hospital (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Baptist Hospital (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Counseling Group (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Beach Psychiatric Center (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Willow Oak Farm (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Westbrook Psychiatric (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Education--Classes, Seminars, Workshops (Box 30-34)
  - Community College Workshop (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Competency: Gideon, William L. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Judicial Seminar on Alcohol and Highway Safety--Manual (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Midwestern and Eastern Areas Alcohol Education and Training Programs (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Students Organization for Developing Attitudes--Manual #1 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Trainer Catalog--Substance Abuse (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Training Alcoholism Personnel (Box 30, Folder 10-12)
  - Training and Education Task Force (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Students Organization for Developing Attitudes Training Manual--August 1974 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Group Work Approaches--February-April 1975 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Fishersville Workshops--Group Counseling--7-9 April 1975 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Individual Counseling Approaches--Level III--19-21 May 1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Individual Counseling Approaches--Level II (A)--9-11 June 1975 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Individual Counseling Approaches--Level II (B)--23-25 April 1975 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Management and Staff Integration--4-6 August 1975 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Treatment of the Alcoholic with the Family--25-27 August 1975 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Health Directors Conference--7-9 September 1975 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Group Interaction--I (C)--5-9 October 1975 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Case Problem Conference--19-22 October 1975 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Probation and Parole (David Phillips) 6 January 1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Lynchburg VASAP Personnel--14-15 February 1976 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Alcoholism Program Coordinators Workshop--2-5 March 1976 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation Workshop--14-17 March 1976 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Introduction to Alcoholism--Nurses 23 March 1976 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Alcoholism Supervisors Workshop--25-28 April 1976 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Alcoholism Counselors Group Interaction Workshop--23-27 May 1976 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Prevention of Alcoholism Workshop--11-16 July 1976 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Alcoholism Halfway House Workshop--25-30 July 1976 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - VASAP Directors Workshop--12-15 October 1976 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Group Interaction--24-28 October 1976 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Competency Training for Non-degreed Professionals in Alcoholism: Project Summary--November 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Recover from Alcoholism--Longwood College 3 November 1976 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholism Counseling--Individual Advanced--9-12 November 1976 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Crisis Intervention with Alcoholic--5-8 December 1976 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Overview of Alcoholism--Teaching to Community Colleges 20 January 1977 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Introduction to Alcoholism for Nurses 25 January 1977 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Fundamentals of Alcoholism--26-27 February 1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Principles, Methods, and Techniques of Clinical Supervision--1-4 March 1977 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Council on Social Welfare 31 March 1977 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Alcoholism and Industry--3-5 April 1977 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Principles, Methods, and Techniques in Management of Alcoholism Programs--17-20 April 1977 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Modalities of Treatment--10-13 May 1977 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Training in Group Techniques--18-21 May 1977 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Women's Meeting--10-11 June 1977 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Case Problem Conference--12-15 June 1977--Cancelled (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Overview of Alcoholism--24-29 July 1977 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Treatment of the Alcoholic with Significant Others--14-17 August 1977 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Mid-Atlantic Institute--Therapy for the Family--10-13 October 1977 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Doctors Workshop--Richmond 22 October 1977 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Review Board 28 October 1977 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Alcoholism Counseling--Individual Advanced--8-11 November 1977 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Crisis Intervention with the Alcoholic--4-7 December 1977 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - John Tyler Supervisory Workshop 21 December 1977 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - John Tyler 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Occupational Programs for Troubled Employers and Chemically Dependent Employees--23-24 January 1978 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Addiction 22 February 1978 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Similarities and Differences in Alcohol and Drugs--21-24 March 1978 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Delivery Service 30 March 1978 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Principles, Methods, Techniques in Management of Alcohol Programs--9-12 April 1978 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Principles, Methods, and Techniques of Clinical Supervision--16-19 May 1978 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Certification Primer Workshop 29 June 1978 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - The Effects of Alcohol on the Mother and Her Children 21 October 1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Train the Trainers--12-13 December 1978 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Overview of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse for Nurses--18-19 January 1979 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Concerned Persons for Professionals--25-28 March 1979 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Train the Trainers: Follow Up--5-6 June 1979 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Alcoholism Seminar for Physicians 27 October 1979 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - National Center for Alcohol Education--Phase I Meeting 26 August 1980 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Institute of Alcohol Studies at South Oaks (NY)--Training Program for Alcoholism Counseling--Student Manual 1980-1981 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Conference--Peter Bell--17 May 1988--Cancelled (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Holotropic Therapy and Transpersonal Psychology--15-17 February 1991 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Perfect Daughters/Silent Sons Workshop--Ackerman--3-4 May 1991 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Principles, Methods, and Techniques in Treatment of the Alcoholic--Course REH 523C--Summer 1991 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Treatment of the Alcoholic/Addict with Significant Others-Course REH 551C--Summer 1991 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Dual Diagnosis Workshop 13 November 1993 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Eating Disorders--17-18 June 1994 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Brief Therapy: Solution--Focused Approach to Therapy--10-13 October 1994 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Violence in the Community--6-9 November 1994 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Complex Post-traumatic Stress Reactions and Incest: Approaches to Treatment; Delayed Memory Controversy: An Overview and Suggestions for Practice--29-30 September 1995 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Brief Therapy for Relapse Prevention--2-4 October 1995 (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Articles, Newsletters, Manuals, Reports (Box 34)
  - AJL Newsline (April 1983) (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - The Addiction Letter (July 1988) (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Conclusions of Analytical Survey of the Rand Report on Alcoholism and Treatment (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Controlled Drinking (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Dept. of Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services--Annual report, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Drug Abuse Practitioner Credentialing: An Overview and Status Assessment (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - National Association of Alcoholism Treatment Programs 1981-1985 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - The Networker (Summer 1992) (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter of the American Council on Alcoholism, Inc.--Special edition (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Occupational Programming for Alcoholism--The Consortium (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Registry of Alcoholism Treatment Facilities-December 1975 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Toughlove Notes (Summer 1983) (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Treatment--National Institute on Drug Abuse (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Public Health Congress--Major Public Health Problems for the 1990s and Beyond: Alcohol and Drug Abuse--December 1985 draft (Box 34, Folder 21)
- Alcohol and Drug Abuse Rehabilitation Program (ADERP) - Miscellaneous (Box 35-36)
  - History of Treatment (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
  - Legislation (Box 35, Folder 5-8)
  - Nurses (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
  - Prevention (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
  - Rating scale for alcoholism counselors (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Serving the Deaf Alcoholic in Virginia 1977 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Supervision (Box 36, Folder 6-8)
  - Substance Abuse (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 10-12)
- ADERP/Virginia Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors (VAADAC) (Box 37)
  - History--Richmond 1993 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- ADERP/Virginia Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors (VAADAC) - Newsletters (Box 37)
  - Newsletters--vol. 1, no. 1-12 (September 1976-July 1978) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters--vol. 2, no. 1-8 (August 1978-December 1979) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters--vol. 3, no. 2-5 (February-November 1980) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters--April 1982 (Box 37, Folder 5)
- ADERP/Virginia Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors (VAADAC) - Conferences (Box 37-38)
  - NAADAC Conference--Houston, TX--7-10 August 1983 (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
  - First Annual Conference--27-28 March 1981 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Second Annual Conference--22-24 April 1982 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Third Annual Conference--17-19 March 1983 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Fourth Annual Conference and Meeting--17 March 1984--Panels & Workshops (Box 37, Folder 11-12)
  - Fourth Annual Fall Conference on Alcoholism--7-9 November 1984 (Box 37, Folder 13-16)
  - Fifth Annual Fall Conference on Alcoholism--23-25 October 1985 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Sixth Annual Fall Conference on Alcoholism--10-12 October 1986 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Request for Bids for Conferences (Box 38, Folder 3)
- ADERP/Virginia Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors (VAADAC) - Classes, Seminars, Workshops (Box 38-39)
  - Middle Atlantic Institute--13-16 October 1975 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Crisis Intervention 15 November 1975 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - One to One Counseling 13 March 1976 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - The Alcoholic Family in Recovery 12 June 1976 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Emergent Comprehensive Concept of Alcoholism 18 September 1976 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Middle Atlantic Institute--11-14 October 1976 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Reality Therapy 8 January 1977 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Sexuality and Alcoholism 16 April 1977 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Helping Skills for Alcoholism Counselors a la Carkhuff 18 June 1977 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Controlled Drinking 17 September 1977 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Addiction 14 January 1978 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Family of the Alcoholic 13 March 1978 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Burnt Out Counselor 17 June 1978 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Motivating the Dependent Person 16 September 1978 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Alcohol and Adolescence 27 January 1979 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - 'Diagnosing Alcoholism: A Neurological-based Approach-27 January 1979 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - The Woman Alcoholic 15 June 1979 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Alcoholic Minorities: The Gay Community 21 September 1979 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - How to Break the Denial of the Alcoholic 11 January 1980 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Alcohol Abuse and Black America 15 March 1980 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Alcoholism and Depression 14 June 1980 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Spirituality 13 September 1980 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Pharmacology of Drugs/Interaction with Alcohol 17 January 1981 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Sobriety 28 March 1981 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Counselor Burnout 25 April 1981 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Self-actualization for the Recovering Alcoholic 31 July 1981 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Focus on Drugs other than Alcohol 30 October 1981 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Clinical Supervision Workshop--22-24 March 1982 (Box 39, Folder 7-8)
  - Love Is the Only Answer 14 May 1982 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Certification 23 February 1984 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Neuroscientific Frontiers and Drug Dependence 25 October 1986 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Establishing a Model of Supervision in the Field of Addiction--4-6 March 1987 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Outdoor Recovery Weekend--12-14 June 1987-Cancelled (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Roanoke Certification Courses, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - REH 523C: Overview of Alcoholism--Wakefield, VA 1988 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Multicultural Counseling with Alcoholic/Drug Addicted Clients 1 December 1989 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Education 680--Advanced Counseling Techniques (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Material From a Variety of Workshops (Box 39, Folder 18)
- ADERP/Virginia Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors (VAADAC) - Miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - VAAC Membership Directories (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Tidewater Certification (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - VAAC/VAADAC Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 21)
- ADERP/Richmond Focus (Box 40-42)
  - Richmond Focus 1974 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Richmond Focus 1975 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Focus 1976 (Box 40, Folder 4-5)
  - Richmond Focus 1977 (Box 40, Folder 6-7)
  - Richmond Focus 1978 (Box 40, Folder 8-9)
  - Richmond Focus 1979 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Richmond Focus 1980 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - Richmond Focus 1981 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Focus 1982 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
  - Richmond Focus 1983 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Focus 1984 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Focus 1985 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Focus 1987 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Richmond Focus 1988 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Richmond Focus 1989 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Richmond Focus 1990 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Focus 1993 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - - Plan for the Development of a Statewide Program for the Prevention of Mental Illness, Mental Retardation,and Substance Abuse in Virginia (Box 42, Folder unfoldered)
  - - Interagency Collaboration in Drug Rehabilitation (Box 42, Folder unfoldered)
  - - Enhancing Interagency Collaboration in Drug Rehabilitation: A Consultation Manual (Box 42, Folder unfoldered)
  - - Comprehensive Community Alcoholism Plan (Box 42, Folder unfoldered)
- ADERP/National Files - Organizations (Box 43-44)
  - ADERP--Differential Diagnosis--Reading list (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol and Drug Problems Association (ADPA) (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Alcohol Safety Action Program (ASAP) (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - American Council on Alcoholism, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - American Personnel and Guidance Association (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Association of Halfway House Alcoholism Programs of North America, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Association for Medical Education and Research in Substance Abuse (AMERSA) (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Certification and Reciprocity Consortium/Alcohol and Other Drugs, Inc. (CRC/AODA) (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Counselors Alcoholism Addictions Related Dependencies (CAARD) (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Drug and Alcohol Nursing Association, Inc. (DANA) (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Friends for Sobriety (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Group Counseling Service, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Institute of Transpersonal Psychology (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - International Doctors in Alcoholics Anonymous (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Maryland Alcoholism Counselors Certification Board (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Men for Sobriety (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - NAADAC Ethics (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - NAADAC--Information Packet, Including HR 462, a Bill to Establish a National Commission to Study Effectiveness of Treatment Programs (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - National Association of Alcoholism Treatment Programs (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - National Center for Alcohol Education (NCAE) (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - NCAE--Trainer Guidelines for Using the Alcoholism-specific Supplement (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - NCAE--Quarterly Reports--January-November 1976 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - National Clearinghouse for Alcohol Information (Box 43, Folder 23)